Today's share analysis is
of ICICI Lombard General Insurance, which we
also know as ICICI CI GI. So, the
analysis will be on this. The analysis will be on this
because its result has come. Let
me show you that result once,
what has come, how has it come, that is, when has it come. Its
result, the
result of the March quarter, came on
Tuesday, April 16, 24. Today is the
18th, so the result came two days ago and we will
discuss in detail
what opportunity is being created here in buy, sell, hold.
First of all, let's take a look at the news,
what is in the news,
it is being said in the headlines that
5 hours ago from the side of the investors, India's
ICICI Lombard hits record high as
quarterly profit jumps. Okay, so its
profit has jumped, which means that its
result is good somewhere.
Seven hours ago, MTOU also told that
ICICI Lombard General Insurance net
profit climbs in  Fiscal Q4: Okay, so
its net profit has gone up in the March quarter.
Similarly, Reuters reported 19 hours
ago that ICICI Loba Gener
Insurance Q4 PAT i.e. profit after
tax was 5.20 billion. So, of course,
its financial results have been good somewhere
and let us
also see how much it has surprised the market. So, if
we look at the market and how it has
surprised, then in terms of earnings,
it has surprised the market positively by 0.04 percent
and in terms of revenue, it has surprised by
1.24 percent, so that means somewhere
it has surprised positively in terms of both earnings and
revenue, which can
become a good buying opportunity for you. So, now, we used to
check on our three parameters here,
first we used to look at the technicals, then we used to look at the fundamentals,
then we used to see
what the FII DI data is saying and what it is doing. So, first of all,
we will check all that.  First let us do
technical analysis
and first of all we come to the monthly time frame, so once
we have come here on the monthly time frame, let
me reset it once
and then discuss further, so see
here on the monthly time frame, this price is
running at an all-time high, okay, it is
running at an all-time high and it is breaking all its
resistances, prior resistances, whatever
it had, so
it can be said that somewhere
this is a good buying opportunity, okay, there is a
good buying opportunity here
and now if we talk about whether it should be
purchased here and should it move or not, then
if you have the money then
I wait that it at least reaches
its upper level, the upper level, that is, it is
saying 17229, that is, above 1730, if this month
it closes in the green candle, then of
course there is a good buying
opportunity there, if you do not have patience  No,
if you want to do it right now, then it can still be done. So
here, if you do it on a monthly time
frame, then
I will
tell you what kind of strategy should be there. First of all, what should be your target? So,
look at the target, there are
some targets here. According to one, you
can see here that it should
go up as deep as it had made here, that is,
according to 57, your target is
coming here, that is, from 17 15 to 57,
if we go up, then let us see
how far it goes. I will show you once at 57, let us see
how far it is going at 57. If we
look at it, it is 38 45 57, then
2683, that is, you can say that if it
goes to 2600 50 or say 2700, okay, that is, the first target, then
your 2700 should be here on the monthly time frame.
Okay, 2700 is your
first target on the monthly time frame.  If you don't like the target,
you
can right-click on the 10 MA on the 10 time frame.
This blue line you see is the
10 EMA. Keep
right-clicking on it until it closes above it on the 10 time frame.
When it closes below it, you should exit from there.
Now let's see
what your stop loss should be.
I think the stop loss you should keep
here should be at least
1380, or 1400. You will
keep your stop loss here according to the monthly time frame.
After doing this, now we
move to the weekly time frame and
discuss it there as well. So, let's
discuss the weekly time frame.
First, erase the drawing,
set it up once, and then
discuss it again here. So, if
we look carefully at the weekly time frame again,
then somewhere on the overs, it has
broken its resistance and come out above it.
If we look carefully here,
So it is repeatedly respecting its resistance,
but this time it is using the
resistance as its support and
going up. So look here, its first
resistance was here, it respected it, went
down quite a bit, then
came here, then respected it, then went
down, then came here, then
respected it, then went down.
After going down quite a bit, it
jumps again and goes up. This time it does
not go down, this time it goes up, and after going up,
it reaches there.
What is it doing with that resistance? It is considering the level of session 20 as a
support up. And let
me tell you here on the weekly time
frame that its result was
good because its result
came on the 16th. So, as soon as the result came, what happened here,
it did
positively. Its price went up
and its result is also positive. It has
surprised the market positively. So, of course,
you have a good buying point here. If you
want to wait till Friday, you can wait, otherwise.  There
is still a buying opportunity here. I have a slight problem where I
feel that what can be done is that as it
moves towards 1737, it may happen that it starts
forming a range bound. If it
closes above 1737, then
you have a good buying opportunity there. What can be done is that
if
you get this opportunity, then what should be your target
and what should be your stop loss, let me
tell you that. If the stop loss is nothing
here, then you should
keep your stop loss as per 1450, your
stop loss should be on the weekly time frame
and what should be your target, so your target is the
10 EA that you are seeing from here in 10 EM or write this 21 EA that
you are seeing, okay,
if you are comfortable writing 10 EA
in weekly, then of course write it.
You should not sell until it closes below that
or else
Look at 21st November, you write it accordingly,
okay, so we have talked about this on the weekly time frame,
now let us go to the daily time
frame and let us talk about this on the
daily time frame as well, so
first I will raise all the rules on the daily time frame, now
see what is happening here, what is its result,
okay, when did its result come,
see here, it came on 16th April and it is a positive
result, and if we look at that time,
it has gone up according to 1.13, okay, it has gone up
and today it is again going
up, so of course if
we look here very carefully, very
carefully, then what is
happening here, a rectangle pattern is forming,
a rectangle pattern is
forming here, I will
show you here very well how the rectangle pattern,
so look carefully here, the
price is in this range, the price is
moving in this range,
okay, what is the price doing, the
price is moving in this range, how can you see this
here  Look, for a
minute, your price is moving in this range
and I will make it a little
transparent so that you can easily
see it here, so see, in this range, the
price did not go above this range
and in a way, if you look here, a cup
with handle pattern is also formed here, okay, a
very small cup with handle pattern is formed,
see, this is your cup, okay, and this is
your handle, and right now that handle is
trying to go up, so
according to me, if you trade on the daily time frame,
then you should wait at
least for it to close above 1730 or what was its high,
this high was 1734, that is,
if it closes above 1734 on the daily time frame, then
that is a very good buying search right now,
so you have to wait here for two to four days, until
it closes above 1735, according to
me, it is not right to buy here, the
rest is your wish, so if you
buy it accordingly, then I will
tell you what should be the stop loss and your target, so accordingly  So your
stop
loss should be at least 1500, you should
keep your stop loss there, this
should be your stop loss or if
you are very aggressive then you
can keep your stop loss near 1600, 1500 for very conservative
and 1600 for aggressive traders,
so according to that, what should be your target,
in the target you should write this red line
which is 50 SM,
okay, keep writing it until it closes below this,
you should
not sell here, if it closes below this
then sell, so this was our
complete analysis on monthly, weekly and daily time frames in technical analysis, now let's
see its fundamental result,
where we will
also get to see the financial result of March quarter, so this is
ICICI Loba General Insurance Company
Limited, it is known as ICICI GI in NC
market.  The
cap
is ₹8430 crore. The current price is ₹1711.
It has placed targets of ₹1814 and ₹1055.
If we look at its trend here, it is undoubtedly
going in an uptrend and consolidation is taking place somewhere here.
When it
breaks the consolidation, then of course,
there will be very good returns.
You can see in these years as well that it is on the rise
and it is also on the rise in five years.
It is also on the rise in 10 years and it is at an all-time high in Max as well. So, of
course, this is a very good
stock. What is the pros? The company is almost
debt-free. The company is
paying out a healthy dividend as per 29.6%. The
only cons are that its
promoter holding has decreased in the last 3
years, which is 3.98%.
In peer comparison, of course, its sector is
insurance. It
comes in the finance and investment industry and its
ranking is fifth. The first is Life
Insurance. The second is SBI Life and the
third is SDFC Life Insurance.  Fourth is
ICICI Prov Life and fifth is
ICICI Lombard, so it
also comes in the ranking, that is, it is also a leader in the sector.
Once we look at the quarterly results here,
if we look at the quarterly results
here, then in the December quarter
it made 5.75 in CESS and in March it made 5367,
that is, it has increased, operating profit has
increased from 537 to 669, PBT has
increased from 574 to 698, net profit has increased
from 431 to 520, that is, it has also increased, that is,
its
final result on overall OQ basis is quite good. Once we
analyze its result on YOY basis also, then on YOY basis
we will see March 23 and March
24, then in March 23 the sales were
4519 and now in March 24 it has become 5367,
that is, there has been an increase in operating profit, whereas
in March 2023 its - 355  It was running and
now it is 669. Okay, you can guess, from
here the PPT has increased from 573 to 698, which means it has
also increased and the net profit has also increased from 437 to
520, which means overall it can be said
that this is a very
good result on a YOY basis and a
very good result on a QoQ basis as well. Once we go
here, let us also know what the AIT data is doing,
what the promoters are doing,
so if we look here,
in December 2023, its promoters were at 47.9 per
cent and in March it has increased to 51.2 per cent.
Okay, here we have to pay attention,
this is read as 35.4 per cent. So
in such a case, when the promoters increase their stake, then
somewhere or the other some insider investment is taking place in that company.
Okay, that
means a lot of positivity can be seen here.
FIIs have also increased to
3.05. FIIs are also not taking any name of cutting.
Of course, here too
both FIIs and promoters are positive,
which means this company will
give its price positively. It has increased from 7.86 to 15.96, which means there has been an
increase, the government from 0.10 to 0.10,
this is the same, the public from 9.09 to 9.59, so of course if we
look at its share holding pattern, that too is positive,
its FII, DI data, promoters, all that
is positive, in this the fundamental financial
result both on QoQ basis and on
YoY basis is also quite good here
and as per the pattern that I have shown you here, a
rectangle pattern is being formed on the daily time frame or we
can say that it is getting consolidated, so according to that also,
opportunities are
visible here in all three time frames - monthly, weekly and daily. So, according to my analysis done till now,
ICI Nerd is a very
good stock, as far as I feel, whatever may be happening
in the rest of the market.  Maybe, okay, this is
just my analysis. Keep in mind that I
am not a semi-registered advisor, so
you have to do some research yourself
and this is my analysis, it may be different from yours.
So this was the
complete analysis of ICICI GI. Hope you
liked it. Lastly, I would like to say one thing
that you have to diversify your portfolio,
manage the risk
and avoid tips, calls and
recommendations.
Thank you very much for giving so much of your time.